RG 062:163, Town of Windham
Connecticut State Library
Town of Windham records
1805-2012
Connecticut State Library
Windham (Conn.)
101.5 cubic feet
School, vital, tax, financial, and welfare records for the town of Windham and city of Willimantic.
RG062_163
Multiple
Historical Note
The town of Windham was incorporated in May 1692. The City of Willimantic was incorporated in January 1893. The Town of Windham and City of Willimantic consolidated on July 1, 1983.
Scope and Content
School, vital, tax, financial, and welfare records for the town of Windham and city of Willimantic.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Tax assessment -- Connecticut -- Windham -- Registers; Taxation -- Connecticut -- Windham -- Registers; Local taxation -- Connecticut -- Windham -- Registers; Property tax -- Connecticut -- Windham -- Registers; School enrollment -- Connecticut -- Windham -- Statistics; Public welfare -- Connecticut -- Windham; Voter registration -- Connecticut -- Windham
Places:
Willimantic (Conn.) -- Records and correspondence; Windham (Conn.) -- Records and correspondence; Windham (Conn.) -- Statistics, Vital
Restrictions on Access
Welfare files (Accessions 1986-067) are restricted by Connecticut General Statutes §1-210(b)(10), §17b-90, §42-471, and §45a-754.
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1805-2012
  - T000655
    - Rate bills, 1805-1830 (Box Box 1)
    - Sixth School District register, 1875-1876 (Box Box 1)
  - 1986-045
    - Abatement list, 1918; 1 bundle (Box Box 1)
      Includes uncollected taxes, 1916.
    - Assessor's reports, 1919-1927; 1 bundle (Box Box 1)
      Includes taxes paid, 1913.
    - Board of Engineers of the Fire Department rosters, 1899-1909; 1 bundle (Box Box 1)
    - Board of Relief assessments, 1918-1929; 2 bundles (Box Box 1)
    - Certified election returns, 1916 November 7; 1 bundle (Box Box 1)
    - Collector's reports to treasurer, 1910-1912; 1 bundle (Box Box 1)
    - Collector's statements, 1913-1914; 1 bundle (Box Box 1)
    - Conditional Bill of Sales and various other legal documents registered with town clerk, 1921-1922; 1 bundle (Box Box 1)
    - Elector applications, 1912, 1927-1930; 2 bundles (Box Box 1)
    - Electors registering in other towns, 1934; 1 bundle (Box Box 1)
    - Military exemptions, 1895-1912; 1 bundle (Box Box 1)
      Includes notices, 1931.
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1899, 1904, 1919-1928, 1965-1967; 1 bundle (Box Box 1)
      Contains military and commercial business matters and lists of names.
    - School accounts, 1930-1932, 1937; 3 bundles (Box Box 1)
    - Sworn statement about wagons owned, 1903; 1 bundle (Box Box 1)
    - Town meetings, 1897, 1916 October 2; 2 bundles (Box Box 1)
    - Voting and election miscellaneous documents, 1895-1896, 1903-1928; 2 bundles (Box Box 1)
    - Sexton reports, 1892-1923 (Box Boxes 2-3)
      Unarranged.
      For later sexton reports see accession 2013-053.
  - 1986-067
    These files are RESTRICTED. See Restrictions on Access note above.
    - Town welfare case files, 1930-1976 (Box Boxes 1-77)
    - Town welfare disbursements, 1930-1976 (Box Boxes 78-97)
    - Administrative files, 1930-1976 (Box Boxes 98-106)
    - Town welfare grocery accounts, 1930-1976 (Box Boxes 107-109)
  - 2013-052
    - Windham tax abstracts
      Tax abstracts for Windham starting in 1872 are not assigned box or item numbers. Researchers should request items by indicating year up to 1944 by indicating year. 1917 was not transferred to the Connecticut State Library.
      - 1820, 1821, 1822, 1823, 1824, 1825, 1826, 1830, 1834, 1835 (Box Box 1)
        There is one undated volume in this box, noted as "Possibly c.1829".
      - 1844, 1845, 1846, 1847, 1850, 1852, 1853, 1854, 1855, 1856, 1857, 1858, 1859 (Box Box 2)
      - 1860, 1861, 1863, 1864, 1865, 1866, 1867, 1868 (Box Box 3)
      - 1872, 1873, 1874, 1875, 1876, 1877, 1878, 1879, 1880, 1881, 1882, 1883, 1884, 1885, 1886, 1887, 1888, 1889, 1890, 1891, 1892, 1893, 1894, 1895, 1896, 1897, 1898, 1899, 1900, 1901, 1902, 1903, 1904, 1905, 1906, 1907, 1908, 1909, 1910, 1911, 1912, 1913, 1914, 1915, 1916, 1918, 1919, 1920, 1921, 1922, 1923, 1924, 1925, 1926, 1927, 1928, 1929, 1930, 1931, 1932, 1933, 1934, 1935, 1936, 1937, 1938, 1939, 1940, 1941, 1942, 1943, 1944, 72 volumes
    - Willimantic tax abstracts
      Tax abstracts for Willimantic are not assigned box or item numbers. Researchers should request items by indicating year up to 1944 by indicating year.
      The following years were not transferred to the Connecticut State Library, 1837-1845, 1851, 1854, 1855, 1857, 1858, 1875, 1894, 1927.
      A range of years indicate multiple years in a single volume. Years listed twice indicate mutplie volumes labeled for that year.
      - 1833-1836, 1846, 1847, 1848-1849, 1852, 1853, 1856, 1859, 1860, 1861, 1862, 1863, 1864, 1865-1866,, 1867-1872, 1871, 1873, 1874, 1876-1878, 1879-1882, 1881, 1883-1884, 1883-1884, 1885, 1886, 1887, 1888, 1889, 1890, 1891, 1892, 1893, 1895, 1896, 1896, 1897, 1898, 1899, 1900, 1901, 1902, 1903, 1904, 1905, 1906, 1907, 1908, 1909, 1910, 1911, 1912, 1913, 1914, 1915, 1916, 1917, 1918, 1919, 1920, 1921, 1922, 1923, 1924, 1925, 1926, 1928, 1929, 1930, 1931, 1932, 1933, 1934, 1935, 1936, 1937, 1938, 1939, 1940, 1941, 1942, 1943, 1944, 82 volumes
  - 2013-053
    For earlier sexton reports see accession 1986-045.
    - Sexton reports, 1938-1987 (Box Box 1)
    - Sexton reports, 1988-2012 (Box Box 2)
  - 2014-010
    - Willimantic Treasurer journal, 1890-1898; 1 volume (Box Item 1)
      On spine: "A"
    - Willimantic Treasurer journal, 1898-1908; 1 volume (Box Item 2)
      On spine: "B"
    - Willimantic Treasurer journal, 1908-1919; 1 volume (Box Item 3)
      On spine: "C"
    - Willimantic Treasurer journal, 1919-11926; 1 volume (Box Item 4)
      On spine: "D"
    - Record of electors, 1928-1932; 1 volume (Box Item 5)
    - Record of electors, 1932-1934; 1 volume (Box Item 6)
    - Record of electors, 1935-1937; 1 volume (Box Item 7)
    - Record of electors, 1938-1939; 1 volume (Box Item 8)
    - Record of electors, 1940-1955; 1 volume (Box Item 9)
    - Record of electors, 1956-1970; 1 volume (Box Item 10)
    - Record of electors, 1970-1976; 1 volume (Box Item 11)
    - Record of electors, 1977-1994; 1 volume (Box Item 12)
    - Record of electors, 1995-2006; 1 volume (Box Item 13)